Guide to the Archives of the Soviet communist party and Soviet state microfilm collection: Russian State Archives of Social and Political History (Rossiiskii gosudarstvennyi arkhiv sotsialno-politicheskoi istorii - RGASPI)
Hoover Institution Archives
- Fond 17, The Central Committee of the Communist Party of the Soviet Union records, 1903-1965; 1971; 2,457 reels
  - Opis 76: Administration of Affairs of the TsK KPSS. Department of Budget and Finance, 1939-1955, 262 reels) (Reel 2.328-2.406, Reel 2.735-2.758, Reel 2.871-2.899, Reel 2.1096-2.1212, Reel 2.1487-2.1497, Reel 2.1580)
    - Consolidated party budget for the TsK KP(b) of Lithuania and for Moskovskii obkom; consolidated party budgets for and financial reports of the TsK KP(b) of Moldavia, of Mariiskii, Molotovskii, and Murmanskii obkoms and of obkom Nemtsev Povolzhia; estimate sheet and statement about additional financing for Moskovskii obkom, 1941 (Reel 2.346, File 126-135)
    - Consolidated party budgets for and financial reports of Novosibirskii, Omskii, Orlovskii, and Penzenskii obkoms and of Ordzhonikidzevskii and Primorskii kraikoms; financial statement of the Party Classes under Novosibirskii obkom, 1941 (Reel 2.347, File 136-145)
    - Consolidated party budgets for and financial reports of Rostovskii, Riazanskii, Saratovskii, Sverdlovskii, and Severo-Osetinskii obkoms; consolidated party budgets for Smolenskii and Stalingradskii obkoms, 1941 (Reel 2.348, File 146-154)
    - Financial report of Stalingradskii obkom; consolidated party budgets for and financial reports of the TsK KP(b) of Tadzhikistan and Turkmenistan and of Tambovskii, Tatarskii, and Tulskii obkoms; consolidated party budget for Udmurtskii obkom, 1941 (Reel 2.349, File 155-164)
    - Financial report of Udmurtskii obkom; consolidated party budgets for and financial reports of the TsK KP(b) of Uzbekistan, of Khabarovskii kraikom, and of Cheliabinskii obkom; consolidated party budget for the TsK KP(b) of Ukraine; financial report of and statement about additional financing for the TsK KP(b) of Ukraine, 1941 (Reel 2.350, File 165-172)
    - Consolidated party budgets for and financial reports of Checheno-Ingushskii, Chitinskii, Chkalovskii, Chuvashskii, and Yakutskii obkom; consolidated party budgets of the TsK KP(b) of Estonia and of Yaroslavskii obkom; budget estimate for the Marx-Engels-Lenin Institute under the TsK VKP(b), 1941 (Reel 2.351, File 173-184)
    - Budget estimate for the Marx-Engels-Lenin Institute (IMEL) under the TsK VKP(b) (cont.); annual statements of IMEL and its branches and of the Tbilisi branch of the V.I. Lenin Museum; estimate of revenues and expenditures for the V.I. Lenin Central Museum; budget estimates for and correspondence of the branches of the V.I. Lenin Museum; estimates for and statements of the Representatives of the Committee for Party Control under the TsK VKP(b) in provinces (oblasti), territories (krai), and republics; budget estimates for the Leningrad branch of the V.I. Lenin Museum, for the Higher Party School under the TsK VKP(b), for major repair of the buildings that belong to the Higher Party School under the TsK VKP(b), for Higher School of Party Administrators under the TsK VKP(b), for the maintenance of the Lenin Courses under the TsK VKP(b), and for expenses on provincial (oblastnye) party classes presented alphabetically by name of province (from "Í" to "Ó" in Russian), 1941 (Reel 2.352, File 184-195)
    - Budget estimates of expenses on provincial party courses, (provinces names from "Í" to "Ó" (cont.), and from "T" to "ß" in Russian); budget estimate for classes for translators under the TsK VKP(b); contract on transference of the Third Printing House from the Politizdat publishing house to the trust Poligrafkniga; report of the Pravda publishing and printing houses; materials relating to the auditing of obkoms, kraikoms, and the Cabinet of Editors under the Administration of Propaganda and Agitation of the TsK VKP(b); consolidated party budgets for the TsK KP(b) of Azerbaijan and Armenia and of Altaiskii obkom, 1941 and 1942 (Reel 2.353, File 195-203)
    - Financial report of the TsK KP(b) of Armenia; consolidated party budgets for and financial reports of Arakhangelskii, Bashkirskii, Buriat-Mongolskii, Vologodskii, Voronezhskii, and Gorkovskii obkoms; consolidated party budgets for the TsK KP(b) of Georgia and of Dagestanskii obkom, 1942 (Reel 2.354, File 204-215)
    - Consolidated party budgets for Dagestanskii(cont.), Ivanovskii, Kirovskii obkoms, and Kabardino-Balkarskii obkom; consolidated party budgets for and financial reports of the TsK KP(b) of Kazakhstan and Kirgizia and of Kalmykskii obkom; financial report of the TsK KP(b) of the Karelo-Finnish SSR, 1942 (Reel 2.355, File 215-222)
    - Financial report of Kirovskii obkom; consolidated party budgets for and financial reports of Komi, Kuibyshevskii, and Leningradskii obkoms, and of Krasnodarskii and Krasnoyarskii kraikoms; consolidated party budgets for the TsK KP(b) of the Karelo-Finnish SSR and for Mariiskii, Mordovskii, and Murmanskii obkoms, 1942 (Reel 2.356, File 223-233)
    - Financial reports of Mariiskii, Mordovskii, and Murmanskii obkoms; consolidated party budgets for and financial reports of Molotovskii, Moskovskii, Omskii, and Novosibirskii obkoms; consolidated party budgets for Orlovskii obkom and Ordzhonikidzevskii kraikom, 1942 (Reel 2.357, File 234-243)
    - Financial reports of Orlovskii obkom (cont.); consolidated party budgets for and financial reports of Penzenskii, Riazanskii, Saratovskii, Severo-Osetinskii, and Stalingradskii obkoms and of Primorskii kraikom; consolidated party budgets for Sverdlovskii, Smolenskii and Tambovskii obkoms, for Stavropolskii kraikom, and for the TsK KP(b) of Tadzhikistan; semi-annual financial report of Sverdlovskii obkom, 1942 (Reel 2.358, File 243-252)
    - Consolidated party budgets for Tambovskii (cont.) and Tatarskii obkoms; financial reports of the TsK KP(b) of Tadzhikistan and of Tambovskii obkom; consolidated party budgets for and financial reports of the TsK KP(b) of Turkmenistan and Uzbekistan and of Tulskii and Udmurtskii obkoms; consolidated party budgets for Khabarovskii kraikom and for Checheno-Ingushskii and Chkalovskii obkoms, 1942 (Reel 2.359, File 252-266)
    - Consolidated party budgets for Chkalovskii (cont.), Chuvashskii, and Yakutskii obkoms; financial reports of Khabarovskii kraikom and of Checheno-Ingushskii, Chitinskii, Chkalovskii, Chuvashskii, and Yakutskii obkoms; consolidated party budgets for and financial reports of Cheliabinskii and Yaroslavskii obkoms; report of the Pravda publishing and printing houses, 1942 (Reel 2.360, File 266-276)
    - Reports of and financial estimates for the V.I. Lenin Central Museum and its branches; report of and financial estimates for the Marx-Engels-Lenin Institute (IMEL) under the TsK VKP(b); correspondence between the Higher Party School under the TsK VKP(b) and the Central Committee of the International Organization for Assistance to the Fighter of Revolution (MOPR) of the USSR; materials relating to the collecting of warm clothes and underwear for the Red Army in the republics, territories (krai), and provinces (oblast) conducted by the Central Committee of the VLKSM (All-Union Young Communists League), 1942 (Reel 2.361, File 277-283)
    - Regulation and instruction about auditing commissions in the VLKSM (All-Union Young Communists League); materials relating to the collecting of warm clothes and underwear for the Red Army by the political departments of the USSR GULAG under the NKVD (People's Commissariat for Internal Affairs); financial reports of the TsK KP(b) of Azerbaijan and Armenia, of Altaiskii kraikom and of Bashkirskii obkom; financial estimates for local party committees, estimates of additional financing and organizational charts with salary indication for the TsK KP(b) of Azerbaijan and Belorussia; consolidated party budgets and financial reports of the TsK KP(b) of Armenia and of Arakhangelskii obkom; financial reports of the TsK KP(b) of Belorussia, of Buriat-Mongolskii and Vologodskii obkoms; consolidated party budgets and financial estimates for party schools under Arakhangelskii, Bashkirskii, and Buriat-Mongolskii obkoms, 1942 and 1943 (Reel 2.362, File 283-292)
    - Consolidated party budgets for and financial reports of Voronezhskii and Gorkovskii obkoms; consolidated party budget for Vologodskii obkom; financial report of the TsK KP(b) of Georgia, report of the Tbilisi branch of the Marx-Engels-Lenin Institute; annual statement of the Tbilisi branch of the V.I. Lenin Museum; estimates of expenses for party schools attached to the TsK KP(b) of Georgia and of Kazakhstan; financial reports of Dagestanskii, Ivanovskii, and Irkutskii obkoms, 1943 (Reel 2.363, File 293-299)
    - Consolidated party budgets, organizational charts with salary indication, and estimates of additional financing and expenses for party courses under Dagestanskii, Ivanovskii, Kabardinskii, and Kalininskii obkoms; report of the Irkutsk Provincial Commission about the collecting of warm clothes for the Red Army; financial reports of the TsK KP(b) of Kazakhstan, Kirgizia, and the Karelo-Finnish SSR, of Kabardino-Balkarskii, Kalmykskii, and Kemerovskii obkoms; consolidated party budget for and financial report of the Kirovskii obkom, 1943 (Reel 2.364, File 300-306)
    - Consolidated party budgets and financial estimates of expenses for party courses under the TsK KP(b) of the Karelo-Finnish SSR, of Kalmykskii, Kirovskii, Komi, Kemerovskii, Krymskii, and Kuibyshevskii obkoms; financial reports of Komi obkom and of Krasnodarskii and Krasnoyarskii kraikoms; consolidated party budget for and financial report of Kuibyshevskii obkom, 1943 (Reel 2.365, File 307-312)
    - Consolidated party budgets and financial estimates of expenses for party courses under Altaiskii, Krasnodarskii, Krasnoyarskii, and Stavropolskii kraikoms and under Kurganskii, Kurskii, and Moskovskii obkoms; consolidated party budget for and financial report of Leningradskii obkom; financial estimates of expenses and additional financing for the TsK KP(b) of Kirgizia and Latvia, 1943 (Reel 2.366, File 313-319)
    - Financial reports of the TsK KP(b) of Latvia and Moldavia and of Mariiskii obkom; organizational charts with salary indication, estimates of additional financing and of expenses for party courses under the TsK KP(b) of Lithuania, Moldavia, and Tadzhikistan; consolidated party budgets for and financial reports of Molotovskii, Moskovskii, and Novosibirskii obkoms; financial report of Murmanskii obkom; consolidated party budgets and estimates of additional financing for party courses of Leningradskii obkom, 1943 (Reel 2.367, File 320-328)
    - Consolidated party budgets and estimate sheets of additional financing for party courses of Mariiskii, and Molotovskii obkoms; consolidated party budgets for Mordovskii, Murmanskii, and Novosibirskii obkoms; consolidated party budgets for and financial reports of Omskii, Orlovskii, Penzenskii, and Rostovskii obkoms and of Primorskii kraikom; consolidated party budgets for Riazanskii obkom, 1943 (Reel 3.368, File 328-337)
    - Consolidated party budgets for and financial reports of Saratovskii, Sverdlovskii, Severo-Osetinskii, and Smolenskii obkoms; consolidated party budgets, estimates of additional financing, and financial estimates for party courses under Rostovskii, Riazanskii, and Saratovskii obkoms and organizational charts with salary indication for the city party committees (gorkoms) of the said obkoms; financial report of Stavropolskii kraikom; consolidated party budgets for Stalingradskii obkom, 1943 (Reel 3.369, File 338-343)
    - Financial report of Stalingradskii obkom; consolidated party budgets for and financial reports of the TsK KP(b) of Tadzhikistan, Turkmenia, and Uzbekistan and of Tambovskii, Tatarskii, Tulskii, and Udmurtskii obkoms; consolidated party budgets, estimates of additional financing, and financial estimates for party courses under Stalingradskii, Tambovskii, Tatarskii, and Tulskii obkoms, 1943 (Reel 3.370, File 344-358)
    - Estimates of additional financing, financial estimates, and organizational charts with salary indication for party courses under the TsK KP(b) of Turkmenia and Uzbekistan; financial report of the TsK KP(b) of Ukraine; consolidated party budgets for and financial reports of Ulianovskii obkom and Khabarovskii kraikom; two consolidated party budgets for Cheliabinskii obkom; consolidated party budgets and estimates of additional financing for Udmurtskii, Ulianovskii, and Cheliabinskii obkoms, 1943 (Reel 3.371, File 359-364)
    - Financial reports of Checheno-Ingushskii, Cheliabinskii, Chuvashskii, and Yakutskii obkoms and of the TsK KP(b) of Estonia; consolidated party budgets for and financial reports of Chitinskii and Chkalovskii obkoms; consolidated party budgets, estimates of additional financing, and financial estimates for party courses under Chehceno-Ingushskii, Chitinskii, and Chkalovskii obkoms; financial reports and estimates of expenses for party courses and additional financing for the TsK KP(b) of Ukraine and Estonia; consolidated party budgets for Yaroslavskii obkom, 1943 (Reel 3.372, File 365-372)
    - Financial reports of Yaroslavskii obkom; consolidated party budgets, estimates of additional financing, organizational charts with salary indication, and financial estimates for party courses under Chuvashskii, Irkutskii, Yakutskii, and Yaroslavskii obkoms; annual statement of the Foreign Languages Publishing House; annual statement of the Pravda publishing and printing houses; financial reports of and estimates of expenses for the V.I. Lenin Central Museum and its branches, the Higher Party School under the TsK VKP(b and the Marx-Engels-Lenin Institute under the TsK VKP(b); party budget for the TsK KP(b) of Azerbaijan 1944; financial reports of, and consolidated party budgets and organizational charts with salary indication for the city party committees (gorkoms) under the TsK KP(b) of Azerbaijan, 1943 and 1944 (Reel 2.373, File 373-381)
    - Party budget for and financial report of the TsK KP(b) of Armenia; consolidated party budgets for and financial reports of Altaiskii kraikom, of Arakhangelskii, Astrakhanskii, Brianskii, Buriat-Mongolskii, Velikolukskii, and Vladimirskii obkoms, and of the TsK KP(b) of Belorussia, 1944 (Reel 2.374, File 382-390)
    - Consolidated party budgets for and financial reports of Vladimirskii obkom (cont.); consolidated party budgets for and financial reports of Vologodskii, Voronezhskii, Gorkovskii, Groznenskii, Dagestanskii, and Ivanovskii obkoms and of the TsK KP(b) of Georgia, 1944 (Reel 2.375, File 390-395)
    - Consolidated party budgets for and financial reports of Irkutskii, Kabardino-Balkarskii, Kalininskii, Kemerovskii, and Kaluzhskii obkoms, of the TsK KP(b) of Kazakhstan and Kirgizia, and of the Karelo-Finnish party organization, 1944 (Reel 2.376, File 396-405)
    - Consolidated party budgets for and financial reports of Kirovskii, Kalmykskii, Komi, Kostromskoi, Kurganskii, and Kurskii obkoms and of Krasnodarskii and Krasnoyarskii kraikoms; financial reports of Krymskii and Kuibyshevskii obkoms, 1944 (Reel 2.377, File 406-412)
    - Consolidated party budgets for and financial reports of Kuibyshevskii, Leningradskii, Mariiskii, Moldavskii, Mordovskii, Moskovskii, and Molotovskii obkoms and of the TsK KP(b) of Latvia and Lithuania; financial estimates of expenses for party courses under Kuibyshevskii obkom, 1944 (Reel 2.378, File 413-422)
    - Consolidated party budgets for and financial reports of Murmanskii, Novgorodskii, Omskii, Orlovskii, Penzenskii, and Pskovskii obkoms and of Primorskii kraikom; party budget and financial report of Novosibirskii obkom; consolidated party budget for Rostovskii obkom, 1944 (Reel 2.379, File 423-433)
    - Financial report of Rostovskii obkom; consolidated party budgets for and financial reports of Riazanskii, Saratovskii, Sverdlovskii, Severo-Osetinskii, and Smolenskii obkoms and of Stavropolskii kraikom, 1944 (Reel 2.380, File 434-438)
    - Consolidated party budgets for and financial reports of Stalingradskii, Tambovskii, Tatarskii, Tomskii, and Tulskii obkoms and of the TsK KP(b) of Tadzhikistan and Turkmenistan, 1944 (Reel 2.381, File 439-445)
    - Consolidated party budgets for and financial reports of the TsK KP(b) of Turkmenistan (cont.) and Uzbekistan and of Udmurtskii obkom; financial report of the TsK KP(b) of Ukraine; consolidated party budget for the TsK KP(b) of Ukraine [folder 1], 1944 (Reel 2.382, File 445-453)
    - Consolidated party budget for the TsK KP(b) of Ukraine [folder 1 (cont.) and folder 2]; consolidated party budgets for financial reports of Ulianovskii, Cheliabinskii, Chitinskii, and Chkalovskii obkoms and of Khabarovskii kraikom, 1944 (Reel 2.383, File 453-458)
    - Consolidated party budget for and financial reports of Chkalovskii obkom (cont.); consolidated party budgets for and financial reports of the TsK KP(b) of Estonia and of Chuvashskii, Yakutskii, and Yaroslavskii obkoms; annual statements of the Sovetskaia Sibir publishing house and of the Publishing House for Foreign Language Literature; financial estimates, organizational charts with salary indication, and list of students for the Higher Party School, 1944 (Reel 2.384, File 458-465)
    - Financial estimates for and statements of the V.I. Lenin Museum; statement on the budget of the TsK VLKSM (All-Union Young Communists League), materials related to the Central Newspaper Courses, and documents from the Pravda printing house; registers reflecting the assistance rendered to the liberated regions [from Germans] and collection of warm clothes for the Red Army; turnover balance, list of employees, and statements about the economic and financial situation in the Marx-Engels-Lenin Institute; annual statement of the Higher Party School (VPSh) and organizational charts with salary indication and financial estimates of expenses for the External Higher Party School (Zaochnaia vysshaia partiinaia shkola); information about the financial situation in the Higher School of Party Administrators; lists of the students attending Lenin Courses who participated in the Resistance (partisan) movement; materials relating to the auditing of Kabardino-Balkarskii and Arakhangelskii obkoms and Altaiskii kraikom, 1944 (Reel 2.385, File 466-472)
    - Materials relating to the auditing of Astrakhanskii, Bashkirskii, Buriat-Mongolskii, Voronezhskii, Voroshilovgradskii, Ivanovskii, Kaluzhskii, Kemerovskii, Kirovskii, Kurskii, Mordovskii, Novosibirskii, Orlovskii, Rostovskii, Saratovskii, Smolenskii, Stalingradskii, Udmurtskii, and Chitinskii obkoms and Krasnoyarskii and Stavropolskii kraikoms, the TsK KP(b) of Kazakhstan, and the Pravda publishing house; financial estimates of expenses for the Leningrad branch of the V.I. Lenin Museum, party courses, the S.M. Kalinin Museum, and the Institute of History of the VKP(b), 1944 (Reel 2.386, File 473-481)
    - Consolidated party budgets and financial estimates of expenses for party schools under the TsK KP(b) of Azerbaijan; consolidated party budget and financial report of the TsK KP(b) of Azerbaijan for nine months of 1944; financial report of the TsK KP(b) of Azerbaijan; consolidated party budgets for and financial reports of Altaiskii kraikom, of the TsK KP(b) of Armenia, and of Arakhangelskii, Astrakhanskii, and Bashkirskii obkoms; annual statement, financial estimates, and estimate sheets of additional financing for the TsK KP(b) of Armenia, 1945 (Reel 2.387, File 482-493)
    - Consolidated party budget for and financial report of the TsK KP(b) of Belorussia and of Brianskii, Buriat-Mongolskii, and Velikolukskii obkoms; consolidated party budget, explanatory memorandum and organizational charts with salary indication of the city party committees within the Belorussian party organization; financial report and 1946 balance sheet for Brianskii obkom; consolidated party budget for Vladimirskii obkom, 1945 (Reel 2.388, File 494-501)
    - Financial report of Vladimirskii obkom; consolidated party budget for and financial report of Vologodskii, Voronezhskii, Gorkovskii, and Groznenskii obkoms and of the TsK KP(b) of Georgia, 1945 (Reel 2.389, File 502-509)
    - Annual statement of the Tbilisi branch of the V.I. Lenin Museum and of the Vostochno-Sibirskaia Pravda publishing house in Irkutsk Province (oblast); consolidated party budgets for and financial reports of Dagestanskii, Ivanovskii, Irkutskii and Kabardinskii obkoms; materials relating to the auditing of financial and economic activities of Kabardinskii obkom, 1945 (Reel 2.390, File 510-520)
    - Consolidated party budget for and financial report of the TsK KP(b) of Kazakhstan and the Karelo-Finnish Republic and of Kalininskii and Kaluzhskii obkoms; materials relating to the auditing of financial and economic activities of the TsK KP(b) of Kazakhstan; consolidated party budget for Kemerovskii obkom, 1945 (Reel 2.391, File 521-530)
    - Financial report of Kemerovskii obkom; annual statement of the newspaper Kuzbass editorial board in Kemerovskaia province (oblast); consolidated party budgets for and financial reports of the TsK KP(b) of Kirgizia, of Kirovskii, Komi, and Kostromskoi obkoms, and of Krasnodarskii kraikom, 1945 (Reel 2.392, File 531-539)
    - Consolidated party budget for and financial report of Krasnoyarskii kraikom, of Krymskii, Kurganskii, Kurskii, and Kuibyshevskii obkoms, and of the TsK KP(b) of Latvia; report of the newspaper Krasnoyarskii rabochii editorial board; report about activities of the financial/economic sector of Kurskii obkom, 1945 (Reel 2.393, File 540-551)
    - Consolidated party budgets for and financial reports of Leningradskii and Mariiskii obkoms, of the TsK KP(b) of Lithuania and Moldavia; consolidated party budget for Molotovskii obkom, 1945 (Reel 2.394, File 552-558)
    - Financial report of Molotovskii obkom; consolidated party budget and financial estimates for the publishing house of the newspaper Zvezda published in Molotovskaia province (oblast); consolidated party budgets for and financial reports of Mordovskii, Moskovskii, Murmanskii, Novgorodskii, and Novosibirskii obkoms, 1945 (Reel 2.395, File 559-568)
    - Consolidated party budgets for and financial reports of Omskii, Orlovskii, Penzenskii, and Pskovskii obkoms and of Primorskii kraikom; materials relating to the auditing of financial and economic activities of Primorskii kraikom; consolidated party budget for Rostovskii obkom, 1945 (Reel 2.396, File 569-579)
    - Consolidated party budget (cont.) for and financial report of Rostovskii obkom; consolidated party budgets for and financial reports of Riazanskii, Saratovskii, Sverdlovskii, and Severo-Osetinskii obkoms; materials relating to the auditing of financial and economic activities of Severo-Osetinskii obkom; consolidated party budget for Smolenskii obkom, 1945 (Reel 2.397, File 579-587)
    - Financial report of Smolenskii obkom; consolidated party budgets for and financial reports of Stalingradskii, Tambovskii, and Tatarskii obkoms, of Stavropolskii kraikom, and of the TsK KP(b) of Tadzhikistan; materials relating to the auditing of financial and economic activities of Stavropolskii kraikom, 1945 (Reel 2.398, File 588-598)
    - Consolidated party budgets for and financial reports of Tomskii, Tuvinskii, Tulskii, Tiumenskii, and Udmurtskii obkoms and of the TsK KP(b) of Turkmenistan; materials relating to the auditing of financial and economic activities of Udmurtskii obkom, 1945 (Reel 2.399, File 599-610)